## HANS KUDER

hanskuder@gmail.com  $\cdot$  (952) 905-8876

## **OVERVIEW**

Versatile technical leader with over 12 years of experience in software engineering. I enjoy solving deep technical challenges, building great products, and guiding and mentoring other engineers. Proven history of working remotely and with distributed teams. Looking for a high-scale challenge in a high-growth company.

## EXPERIENCE

TuneIn
Staff Software Engineer - Core Platform

San Francisco, CA

October 2017 - Present

Designed and built distributed systems for a streaming media company with 75M active users.

- Guided and executed a split of platform functionality into microservices, running on a multi-region AWS stack using Kubernetes. Planned architecture and inter-service communications. Implemented frameworks and libraries that helped other teams create individual services.
- Improved caching (clustered Redis) and messaging (Kinesis, SQS) infrastructure layers to increase speed, availability, and scalability.
- Implemented several new high-traffic services that supported distribution and growth efforts.
- Mentored and coordinated other engineers. Helped set technical direction and standards across multiple teams. Actively involved in interviewing and hiring.
- Technologies: Go, C#, Python, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS (DynamoDB, Kinesis, EKS, Lambda, ElastiCache, Aurora, SQS)

## Suitable Technologies

Palo Alto, CA

Lead Software Engineer

June 2013 - September 2017

Led the team that built scalable, highly available backend services for the Beam, a remotely operated telepresence robot.

- Led a successful rewrite of the Beam administration application. Built a REST API that provided a common backend for web, mobile, and third-party applications.
- Designed and built a highly-available real-time messaging service for communication between Beams and operators.
- Built a streaming event pipeline for Beam telemetry data. Drove scope and execution for the ingestion service, data streaming, and downstream consumers such as a near-real-time analytics application, a data warehouse, and user notifications.
- Mentored junior engineers. Owned product execution for a variety of customer-facing applications. Worked closely with management to define roles and hire team members.
- Technologies: Python, Django, RabbitMQ, XMPP, Redis, protocol buffers, Angular.js, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Apache Kafka, Cassandra, ElasticSearch

Hii Def

New York, NY

Senior Software Engineer

August 2011 - March 2013

Designed and developed features and services for the Goodsie.com eCommerce platform.

• Implemented a REST API and JS frontend for the Goodsie storefront page builder.

- Created an analytics service for Goodsie.com and Flavors.me.
- Built a CI/CD pipeline for Goodsie.com, allowing our team to release frequently and with confidence.
- Technologies: Python, Django, Flask, Celery, RabbitMQ, Backbone.js, MySQL, AWS

Bloom Health
Software Engineer
April 2010 - August 2011

Built backend services for a health insurance marketplace startup, acquired by WellPoint in 2011.

- Built a recommendation engine for insurance products.
- Contributed features to the core financial transaction system for billing and accounting.
- Implemented a caching layer to speed up product matching and recommendations.
- Technologies: Groovy/Grails, Java, Python, MySQL, Redis, NumPy

MTS Systems Eden Prairie, MN
Systems Software Engineer June 2008 - March 2010

Designed and implemented software to perform real-time control and telemetry for industrial test and automation systems.

- Designed control/DSP loops and GUI operator software for a Formula 1 transmission testing system, a 40-foot rocket fuselage welding robot, and various R&D projects.
- Optimized control code to meet hard-real-time constraints.
- Contributed to internal libraries and tools: An object-oriented C framework for real-time control and a Smalltalk variant for rapid GUI development.
- Technologies: C, Python, DSP/Controls, embedded/real-time OS

EDUCATION

University of Michigan BSE, Electrical Engineering, cum laude Ann Arbor, MI September 2004 - April 2008